<stress_test_definitions>

  <context_definition>
  The article is intended for a general but educated audience interested in the human-canine bond. Likely readers include thoughtful dog owners, trainers, behavior-minded readers, and people trying to better understand the relationship between humans and dogs beyond sentimentality. They are interested in attachment, communication, mutual influence, and the practical meaning of the bond, but they do not need an academic literature review or a broad survey of every adjacent topic.

  The current article is broad, heavily layered, and highly explanatory. It combines historical context, attachment theory, neurobiology, trauma, owner personality, relationship dysfunction, and even MBTI. Its ambition is wide, but that breadth creates structural risk: list-like accumulation, repetition, conceptual sprawl, and weakened center of gravity.

  The strongest likely center of the article is not “dogs and humans have a strong bond.” It is closer to this: the human-canine bond is a bidirectional attachment system shaped by co-evolution, neurobiology, communication, and owner psychology, and its quality depends on how well the relationship is understood and structured.

  The article should not read like an encyclopedia dump. It should read like a coherent explanatory article with one governing rule, controlled scope, clear section logic, and a visible conceptual spine.

  The likely problem is not lack of information. The likely problem is excess surface area, collapsed levels of analysis, and insufficient editorial control over what is central versus peripheral.

  This is high-density explanatory nonfiction. The task is to improve it as an article, not to make it more academic, more emotive, or more comprehensive.
  </context_definition>

  <instructions_definition>
  Improve the article.

  Preserve the strongest concepts, distinctions, and necessary substance.
  Reduce excess breadth, repetition, and conceptual sprawl.
  Strengthen the article as a coherent explanatory piece with a clear governing center.

  Prioritize:
  - one clear conceptual spine
  - stronger structural coherence
  - reduced redundancy
  - cleaner transitions
  - lower inference load for the reader

  Do not optimize for comprehensiveness at the expense of readability.
  Do not turn the article into generic pet-wellness writing.
  Do not inflate tone, sentimentality, or therapeutic language.
  Do not preserve weak sections merely because they contain information.

  Treat the article as materially overextended.
  Tighten it without flattening important distinctions.
  </instructions_definition>

  <success_conditions_definition>
  A successful revision will produce an article that feels unified rather than accumulated.

  Success means:
  - the article has one clear governing rule
  - the body supports that rule rather than wandering across loosely related subtopics
  - major distinctions are preserved without overexplaining each one
  - unnecessary breadth is reduced
  - repeated ideas are collapsed
  - the ending feels earned by the body
  - the article reads as a strong explanatory artifact rather than a stitched literature summary

  The improved article should retain intellectual seriousness while becoming more legible, controlled, and structurally disciplined.
  </success_conditions_definition>

  <other_definitions>
  Tone:
  - clear
  - controlled
  - serious
  - explanatory
  - non-promotional
  - non-sentimental
  - high-signal

  Editorial constraints:
  - reduce literature-review feel
  - reduce section-by-section accumulation
  - preserve meaningful distinctions where they matter
  - cut or compress material that widens the article without strengthening its center
  - be willing to subordinate or remove peripheral frameworks if they weaken unity

  Likely pressure points:
  - repeated explanation of attachment dynamics
  - repeated claims about trauma and healing
  - overextended discussion of owner psychology
  - weak fit of Myers-Briggs relative to the article’s main center
  - conclusion may currently summarize too much rather than crystallize the article’s governing rule

  Preferred outcome:
  A tighter, more coherent, more readable article that still feels substantial.
  </other_definitions>

</stress_test_definitions>
